<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Allison Burtch</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <description>Art archive from 2010-2016</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 16:55:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

    
      <item>
        <title>Numbers on the Board</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/66297142&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/66297142&quot;&gt;Numbers on the Board&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/allisonburtch&quot;&gt;Allison Burtch&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manhattanhenge occurs roughly two weeks before and after the summer solstice. We wanted to create a project that revolved around this timing. All of the sounds begin together, then then become polyrhythmic, and all align together 44 days later at the timing of Manhattanhenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created for Jeff Crouse and Brett Renfer’s Spatial Media class at NYU’s ITP program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info:
johncapogna.com/
andysigler.com/
allisonburtch.net/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2019/03/02/numbers-on-the-board/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2019/03/02/numbers-on-the-board/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mic Jammer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This project was made while a resident at Eyebeam during 2014-2015. The Mic Jammer is an ultrasonic security system that gives people the confidence to know that their smart phone microphones are non-invasively muted. It blasts a ton of ultrasonic noise at a iPhone mems microphone that is above the range of human hearing but still within the sensitive range of the mic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a video explanation I did for &lt;a href=&quot;http://fffff.at/f-a-t-gold-san-francisco/&quot;&gt;FAT GOLD&lt;/a&gt; (the last fffff.at show ever) held in San Francisco:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/128921351&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the video I made to accompany the Eyebeam installation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/120425709&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My description at the time:
We now know that there are machines, cameras and algorithms everywhere that are listening to us. The creepiness and ensuing privacy debacle of products such Hello Barbie and the Samsung Smart Tv, both of which have microphones constantly listening, have been the most frequently mentioned products as of late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about our smart phones, the personal tracker we carry everywhere? What about when you’re having a face-to-face conversation and you wish that the microphone would be turned off (but you still need to use your phone)? Or what about those apps that have access to your microphone? What are they doing with that data? Don’t you wish you could just ‘turn off’ different aspects of hardware, like your microphone or camera?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This requires a hardware, not a software solution because software is infinitely hackable but you can guarantee through hardware that software can’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This device that we made is like taping over your webcam, but for audio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a collaboration with Eric Rosenthal, with whom I have been collaborating since he was my professor at ITP, along with Andy Sigler, who has also helped make some PCBs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 06:32:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2017/09/12/mic-jammer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2017/09/12/mic-jammer/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DARC</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Drone Conference co-organized in 2013. Imagining a near future in which networks of autonomous robots roam the skies. I helped organize the hackathon that was sponsored by Parrot and held at ITP/NYU in October 2013. The archived version of the website is &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20131221051928/http://droneconference.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2017/09/11/drones-aerial-robotics-conference/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2017/09/11/drones-aerial-robotics-conference/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Papers</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;occupied-wall-st-journal&quot;&gt;Occupied Wall St Journal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Occupied Wall Street Journal came out of Zuccotti/Liberty Square in the Fall of 2011. I went there in the midst of a bit of a personal crisis, a friend I was supposed to move out with decided to live with her boyfriend, then we got bedbugs, and so I was staying on a close friend’s couch in Sunset Park. I went to Zuccotti Park the end of the first week of the occupation and found a job with my friend Kevin and the information desk. That time was sometimes spent talking to strangers about what we were doing (everyone, of course, had a different idea of what we were doing), directing other occupiers to whichever meeting they were looking for, and guarding this bucked of donation money (no clue where any of that went). I still remember the generousity of strangers who came with clothes, food, blankets and sleeping bags. I’ll always remember one of the few times I slept there staring at the looming HSBC Bank Building and knowing that this had changed my life and had changed the country and proud of myself that I had gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occupy may have gotten shut down but it created the connections for all of the activism that happened in NYC for the decade to follow. It introduced me to radicals that altered the course of my political education. I got involved with the Occupied Wall St. Journal sometime after they had published their second edution, if I recall correctly. I had written a small blog on Feministing criticizing the OWSJ masthead for being primarily men. (It was not, but two women were working under pseudonyms). They invited me to the Brecht Forum (rip) and allowed to stay, when, in the words of one of the editors they found out I was “a serious person.” There are many other controversies about this paper that is not my story to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a communist editorial project was life changing. I had never had the experience of working on creating a message that both represented the masses but also didn’t speak for them. The OWSJ was printed five times locally, each with a distribution of 100,000 and once nationally – in San Francisco, Houston and Chicago. All editions were translated into Spanish, French, Greek and Arabic. Contributors included well-known writers such as Rebecca Solnit, Barbara Kingsolver, Cornel West, Chris Hedges and Matt Taibbi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the links for these projects are now dead, so I am going to do my best to archive them. There were many people that worked on all of these projects, some anonymously or pseudononymously, and the rest are listed on the masthead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edition 1 - link is &lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/OCCUPY_JOURNAL_1L_spreads.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edition 2 - link is &lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/OCCUPY_JOURNAL_2_spreads.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edition 3 - link is &lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/FINAL_OCCUPY_JOURNAL_3_spreads.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edition 4 - link is &lt;a href=&quot;http://occuprint.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edition 5 - link is &lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/owsj_NatEd_5_spreads.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edition 6 - link is &lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/OWSJ_6_web.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;strike-the-prisons&quot;&gt;Strike the Prisons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following year, some of the same group of people made a paper for what was at the time the largest prison strike in California’s history. The archived site was &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20160325094446/http://striketheprisons.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/prisonstrike.png&quot; alt=&quot;Strike the Prisons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;battle-of-new-york&quot;&gt;Battle of New York&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a paper in the 2016 primaries in support of Bernie Sanders and published a line that unfortunately came true: “a vote for Hillary Clinton could be a vote for Trump.” The archived site was &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20160815061215/http://battleof.nyc/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/battlosofnyc.png&quot; alt=&quot;Strike the Prisons&quot; /&gt;
Download here:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2016/12/31/Papers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2016/12/31/Papers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>School for Poetic Computation</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 06:32:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2015/05/05/SFPC/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2015/05/05/SFPC/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Log Jammer</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 06:32:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2015/05/05/Deep-Lab/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2015/05/05/Deep-Lab/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Log Jammer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/log-jammer.jpg&quot;&gt;log jammer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a cellphone jammer put in a log in the woods, in order to create a safe space in nature. It was tested in the lab (no illegal shit) and was a part of my Master’s thesis at ITP. Part of this project was largely inspired by this Deleuze quote, which went viral on my tumblr:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tumblr-post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://embed.tumblr.com/embed/post/xjUGgQFXpT7hWCC6cs05RQ/98800122613&quot; data-did=&quot;02c121235d29a7f9cb958db770ddf68f11c5be6a&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.allisonburtch.net/post/98800122613/the-problem-is-no-longer-getting-people-to&quot;&gt;https://blog.allisonburtch.net/post/98800122613/the-problem-is-no-longer-getting-people-to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.tumblr.com/post.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/log-jammer2.png&quot; alt=&quot;log jammer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A plane flight used to disconnect us from technology, a walk in the woods and we were alone – yet the subways will soon have cell service and even Canada is putting wifi in all of its national parks. And so we’re at a place where everyone is constantly saying everything…but no one has anything to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who cares if we have endless information, if we’re constantly connected, if we can’t deal with it? How can anything change if we don’t talk to each other, work together? Because really, the problem is no longer getting people to express themselves, but providing any miniscule gap of solitude in which they might eventually find something to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I made a log jammer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The log jammer provides a safe space in the woods, a right to be alone. What a relief to have the right to say nothing, because only then is there a chance of framing the rare, the thing that might be worth saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American phones operate on two different spectrums – GSM-850 and GSM-1900. This “cellphone jammer” creates noise at a specific radio wavelength so that cell transmissions can’t go through. I chose 1900 because that’s what my cell phone is on and doing both would be way too much work. Here’s a link to see it in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then went through dozens of design iterations a pcb design software program called Eagle. You can see some of those iterations here and here. I also put it on Github.
logjammer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just as urban infrastructure (a cell phone tower) is often disguised as a natural environment, I did the opposite – a jammer in a real log in real woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/log-jammer2.png&quot; alt=&quot;log jammer&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/log-jammer3.png&quot; alt=&quot;log jammer&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/log-jammer4.png&quot; alt=&quot;log jammer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Eric Rosenthal, scientist-in-residence at NYU-ITP, for his guidance and direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SELECTED PRESS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently in &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20161009062627/http://www.wired.com/2014/10/fake-log-jams-your-phone/&quot;&gt;WIRED&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20161009062627/http://motherboard.vice.com/de/read/dieser-holzklotz-jammt-dein-telefon-damit-du-es-endlich-aus-der-hand-legst&quot;&gt;VICE Germany&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 06:32:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2015/05/05/log-jammer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2015/05/05/log-jammer/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Dumb Store</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-most-inclusive-mobile-app-platform-ever&quot;&gt;The most inclusive mobile app platform. Ever.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170712083832/http://www.dumbsto.re/&quot;&gt;dumbsto.re&lt;/a&gt; was an inclusive app platform for obtaining information via dumb phones. The Dumb Store is a demonstration of what can be done using dumb phones. It’s an exploration in resisting planned obsolescence and using current technology to its fullest capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dumb Store was an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dumbstore/dumbstore&quot;&gt;open platform for anyone&lt;/a&gt; to submit their dumbphone-compatible &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170418022743/http://www.dumbsto.re/apps&quot;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt;. It was a collaboration between myself and &lt;a href=&quot;https://nas.sr/&quot;&gt;Ramsey Nasser&lt;/a&gt; in 2012-2013. We made the framework on Twilio and it went to the top of hacker news at the time. Twilio generously gave us some credits when a ton of people were using the service that we were paying for. Unfortunately I decided to buy a .re TLD which was expensive and I let it lag and now can’t buy it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;press&quot;&gt;Press:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Village Voice, “How to Make your Dumb Phone Smart” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.villagevoice.com/2013/05/29/how-to-make-your-dumb-phone-smart/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 06:32:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2015/05/05/the-dumb-store/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2015/05/05/the-dumb-store/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WHAT IS MISSING?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://whatismissing.net&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-40&quot; alt=&quot;wim&quot; src=&quot;http://www.allisonburtch.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/wim.png&quot; width=&quot;832&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya Lin’s last memorial, &lt;em&gt;What is Missing?&lt;/em&gt;, is devoted to remembering habitat and species loss. Viewers can add their personal memories and view those from the past. I was the lead researcher for the project from 2010-2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://oceana.org/en/blog/2012/04/maya-lin-asks-what-is-missing&quot;&gt;Oceana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-04-19/maya-lin-issues-warning-to-a-dirty-dying-planet.html&quot;&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artlog.com/2012/24-maya-lins-monument-to-the-environment&quot;&gt;ARTLOG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://e360.yale.edu/feature/maya_lin_a_memorial_to_a_vanishing_natural_world/2545/&quot;&gt;Yale Environment 360&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birds.cornell.edu/roundrobin/2012/04/24/cornell-lab-helps-artist-maya-lin-ask-what-is-missing-on-earth-day-2012/&quot;&gt;Cornell Lab of Ornithology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.post-gazette.com/stories/ae/art-architecture/maya-lin-invites-and-challenges-visitors-to-her-website-to-help-improve-earths-well-being-631914/&quot;&gt;Pittsburgh Post-Gazette&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 06:32:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//what-is-missing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//what-is-missing/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spyke</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/plugin.png&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20160603235836/http://www.allisonburtch.net/illuminator/&quot;&gt;Firefox addon iterates&lt;/a&gt; through all of the html text in your browser and whenever it finds a person or corporation from the data, it illuminates that relationship a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main problem I was trying to solve was how to increase the spread of information about political and corporate relationships without making people go to one place for the data. So, I made an addon that appends brands, individuals and corporations with who they are owned by, other companies of which they are board members, or dates of acquisitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ubiquitous relationships are often complex and unknown. It reveals the connections between corporations, brands and individuals by clarifying the corporate and political power structures of the 1%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appends that person, brand or corporation with who they are owned by, sponsored by, or acquired by. Data was compiled mainly from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://littlesis.org/home/dashboard&quot;&gt;Little Sis API&lt;/a&gt;, lists of lists on Wikipedia, and other corporate watchdog sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;N.B., the data was updated as of May, 2014. As there are infinite data points and everything is constantly changing, I give no guarantee that the data is 100% accurate. There will be bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check out the code on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/allisonburtch/internet_Illuminator&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2014/01/26/internet-illuminator/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2014/01/26/internet-illuminator/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spyke</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Spyke was an in-browser video chat application using using WebRTC, PeerJS, Express, Socket.io and NodeJs on Heroku. I got about 70% of the way into this project and then found a handful of companies doing the same thing but better. This was an attempt at being able to do a peer-to-peer in-browser video chat that bypassed the major corporations (Microsoft and Google).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The requirements are deprecated so here is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/allisonburtch/Spyke&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to the Github.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2014/01/26/Spyke/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2014/01/26/Spyke/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prism Breakup</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;--- layout: post title: PrismBreakup date: 2013-09-24 00:00:00 +0300 description: A series of art and technology events dedicated to exploring and providing forms of protection from surveillance. image: '/images/posts/prismbreakup.png'  ---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prismbreakup.org/&quot;&gt;conference&lt;/a&gt; was organized by Heather Dewey-Hagborg, Aurelia Moser, Ramsey Nasser and myself in the summer of 2013, directly after Edward Snowden leaked information documenting widespread US surveillance and complictiy with Silicon Valley tech companies. The website was kindly made by Dan Pheiffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three day event brough together a wide range of technologists, artists and thinkers, many of who are more well-known today in the privacy/surveillance scene. It was held at the former &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eyebeam.org/&quot;&gt;Eyebeam&lt;/a&gt; location in Chelsea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info go &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prismbreakup.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2013/08/02/Prism-BreakUp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2013/08/02/Prism-BreakUp/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Watching You</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;watching-you-a-love-story&quot;&gt;Watching You: A Love Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/56958834&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching You is an installation in three parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Viewers watched a video, entirely from surveillance cameras, about the artist as a cop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. At the ITP Winter Show, viewers were told that they were currently being surveilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. In exchange for me deleting one of their images from my computer, I would trade them an honest emotion – any sort of feeling, not necessarily about what they just watched, but just a personal emotion. I was surprised by the honesty I received. Many people didn’t care if I deleted their picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching You is documented &lt;a href=&quot;http://yrnotalone.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.bfbifocals.com/portfolio/watching-you-a-love-story/&quot;&gt;BfBifocals&lt;/a&gt;, a working group of designers and artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;College Art Association, CAA Conference. &lt;a href=&quot;http://conference.collegeart.org/2013/artspace/medialounge&quot;&gt;TRANSMEDIATION&lt;/a&gt;. February 13-16, 2013. New York Hilton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artist talk, &lt;a href=&quot;http://eyebeam.org/&quot;&gt;Eyebeam&lt;/a&gt;, Art/Sec(urity) meetup, March 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2013/02/01/Watching-You/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2013/02/01/Watching-You/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bicycles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love riding bikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2008 I co-led a bike tour in Europe. Six teenage boys from Amsterdam to Paris. I laughed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009 I biked from New York City to Los Angeles as part of a tour for the Bicycle Film Festival and 42 Below Vodka, the sponsor of the festival. It was supposed to be a vodka marketing tour but really ended up being the best summer of my life and one of the reasons I moved to NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, I briefly worked for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rapha.cc/cycle-club/&quot;&gt;Rapha&lt;/a&gt; at their pop-up store on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bowery&quot;&gt;Bowery&lt;/a&gt; in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.good.is/posts/cat-6-competitive-commuting-turns-bike-rides-into-races/&quot;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;GOOD Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, I labelled competitive bike commuting “Cat 6″ racing, a reference to competitive cycling in which one begins in Category 5 and progresses to Category 1. The New York Times referenced the &lt;a href=&quot;http://schott.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/12/17/cat-6-and-competitive-commuting/&quot;&gt;terminology&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=9D0DE4DD1630F931A25751C1A9669D8B63&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also &lt;a href=&quot;http://prollyisnotprobably.com/2010/11/good-competitive-commuting-turns-bike-rides-into-races/&quot;&gt;featured&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bikesnobnyc.blogspot.com/2010/11/things-are-looking-up-its-comfort-thing.html&quot;&gt;week&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://bikesnobnyc.blogspot.com/2010/11/bsnyc-friday-kosher-wine-tasting.html&quot;&gt;Bike Snob &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bikesnobnyc.blogspot.com/2011/05/probing-for-answers-cat-6-racing-boom.html&quot;&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordspy.com/words/competitivecommuting.asp&quot;&gt;in&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://texlouisvillebike.blogspot.com/2010/11/cat-6.html&quot;&gt;countless&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.normalguytri.com/journal/tag/news&quot;&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011 I did an loop around the Adirondacks. Had some stupid bike problems, hitch-hiked to the next town (which had a Walmart but not a bike shop) and ended up finishing the tour with a race saddle and Look Keos on a shitty ass front-suspenion Walmart mountain bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012 I did a month-long solo tour from Boston to Prince Edward Island, took a train to Montreal and then biked back.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2013/02/01/bicycles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2013/02/01/bicycles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DNA Spoofing</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;dna-spoofing&quot;&gt;DNA Spoofing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/60928966&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/60928966&quot;&gt;DNA Spoofing: DIY Counter-Surveillance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video was made at ArtHackDay at 319 Scholes in 2013. It’s since been viewed 20k times on line and shown at more places than I can count, including every Holocaust Museum in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we anticipate the possibility of genetic surveillance in the post-apocalyptic present. As humans we are constantly shedding genetic material in public space. It is becoming increasingly common to use those traces for surveillance and reconstruction. As IP spoofing makes anonymous internet browsing possible, DNA spoofing extends that potential by scrambling genetic material, enabling anonymous physical trajectories in tandem with digital. In this spirit, our work offers some DIY techniques for counteracting genetic surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;http://deweyhagborg.com/&quot;&gt;Heather Dewey-Hagborg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ahprojects.com/&quot;&gt;Adam Harvey&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://aureliamoser.com/&quot;&gt;Aurelia Moser&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;arthackday.net/god_mode/&quot;&gt;ArtHackDay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;319scholes.org/&quot;&gt;319Scholes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecreatorsproject.com/blog/how-to-be-anonymous-in-the-age-of-dna-surveillance&quot;&gt;Creator’s Project&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://animalnewyork.com/2013/art-hack-day-god-mode/&quot;&gt;ANIMALNew York&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcodesign.com/1672264/watch-how-to-keep-csi-off-your-dna-trail&quot;&gt;FastCo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2013/01/01/dna-spoofing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2013/01/01/dna-spoofing/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to have fantasies of being a writer. Being a writer is much different that writing. I learned that by working as a blogger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote a couple pieces for Canopy: the first is about &lt;a href=&quot;https://canopy.cr/post/how-we-think-about-strategy-at-canopy&quot;&gt;how we think about strategy&lt;/a&gt;. The second, longer piece talks about &lt;a href=&quot;https://canopy.cr/post/why-is-big-tech-pivoting-on-privacy&quot;&gt;machine learning, privacy and our interconnection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some stuff from a while ago:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to work as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.animalnewyork.com/author/allison/&quot;&gt;journalist&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://animalnewyork.com/&quot;&gt;ANIMAL New York&lt;/a&gt;. Some big pieces include &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.animalnewyork.com/2012/global-political-crisis-why-occupiers-dont-care-if-you-think-occupy-is-dead/&quot;&gt;OWS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.animalnewyork.com/2012/ows-librarians-suing-bloomberg-for-property-destruction-but-it-was-never-about-the-books/&quot;&gt;lawsuits&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.animalnewyork.com/2012/fact-checking-fun-with-ray-kelly/&quot;&gt;stop-and-frisk&lt;/a&gt;, Montreal &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.animalnewyork.com/2012/500000-in-montreal-say-fuck-you-to-emergency-protest-bill/&quot;&gt;student protests&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.animalnewyork.com/2012/anarchism-in-no-church-in-the-wild-as-seen-from-kanye-west-and-jay-zs-ivory-tower/&quot;&gt;Jay-Z&lt;/a&gt;. Have written elsewhere for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indypendent.org/2012/03/30/sex-workers-shadows&quot;&gt;Indypendent&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.good.is/members/allisonburtch&quot;&gt;Good Magazine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//2012/03/15/writings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//2012/03/15/writings/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>trash</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started dumpster diving in Long Beach, CA in 2009 after realizing that the small, organic grocery store I frequented was very, very disorganized. After teaching SAT prep one winter night, I decided to check out the dumpster and found about eighty jars of peanut and almond butter. After that, I started taking a picture every night to document what I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started &lt;a href=&quot;http://thisisyourtrash.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;this blog &lt;/a&gt;because I wanted people to see how much food is thrown away. In fact, about 50% of all harvested food in America is eventually tossed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia Scott of Wallet Pop came along once and interviewed me. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://bargainbabe.com/2010/03/16/bargain-babe-goes-dumpster-diving/&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; was on the front page of AOL.com which resulted in a lot of internet discussion about trash. Just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/#hl=en&amp;amp;tbo=d&amp;amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;amp;q=%22allison+burtch%22+dumpster+diving&amp;amp;oq=%22allison+burtch%22+dumpster+diving&amp;amp;gs_l=hp.3...10219.12662.4.12883.2.2.0.0.0.0.62.111.2.2.0.les%3B..0.0...1c.1.3.psy-ab.gcbq457jJ68&amp;amp;pbx=1&amp;amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.r_cp.r_qf.&amp;amp;bvm=bv.42553238,d.dmg&amp;amp;fp=ea7e351ab9da3dca&amp;amp;biw=1371&amp;amp;bih=710&quot;&gt;google it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allisonburtch.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/4424769171_7d97e62ff5_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone  wp-image-131&quot; alt=&quot;4424769171_7d97e62ff5_z&quot; src=&quot;http://www.allisonburtch.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/4424769171_7d97e62ff5_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;384&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_35&quot; style=&quot;width: 378px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allisonburtch.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/dumpster.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-35 &quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.allisonburtch.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/dumpster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;368&quot; height=&quot;491&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Jess Meany/AnonymousAgent
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//trash/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//trash/</guid>
      </item>
    

    
      
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>About</title>
            <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-me&quot;&gt;About Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I care deeply about change, whether it’s personal, political, societal or spiritual. I love the beauty of the natural world and the beauty of humanity and think that there is no environment in which we are separate; we co-create eachother. I strive to have a confident, unapologetic, honest and clear-eyed understanding of the way the world is and the context in which we all live. This comes from a deep history of studying the nuanced interplay of technology and politics, and how they inform each other to shape the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love applying this wealth of knowledge to help startups build something that might actually have an impact on the way people interact with technology. Please feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;/contact.html&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bio&quot;&gt;Bio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allison Burtch was most recently a strategist and researcher at Canopy, a Brooklyn-based startup creating a private recommendation architecture for the internet. Previously, she was the Speculative Hardware lead at UNICEF, creating the global strategy for drone delivery of vaccines and flood response. She taught “Critical Theory of Technology: Politics, Utopia and Code” at the School for Poetic Computation and was a resident at Eyebeam, the leading art and technology center in the United States, where she created a small ultrasonic hardware device that protects smart phone users from passive audio surveillance. She’s collaborated on such projects as the Dumb Store – a mobile app store for dumbphones, co-organized Prism BreakUp at Eyebeam and the Drones and Aerial Robotics Conference at New York University. She was the lead researcher for Maya Lin’s online memorial “What is Missing?”.  Previously, Allison was an editor of the Occupied Wall Street Journal, a six-edition print publication which was translated into six languages and distributed globally. She led a European biking and camping tour for teenagers, traveled by train from Kazakhstan to Beijing and lived on a boat. She has spoken internationally at conferences and universities. She has a master’s degree from New York University’s Interactive Telecommunications Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;interests&quot;&gt;Interests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;healing, machine learning, adaptogens, artificial intelligence, yoga, cooking, deep learning, mushrooms, explainability of AI, the data exchange model of the internet, privacy, justice, spirituality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-this-site&quot;&gt;About this site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is an archive of the work that I did from 2010-2016. My old site was on wordpress, and some sort of php vulnerability led to that site selling japanese electdronics. I couldn’t fix it so had to start fresh. So I needed to remake it, but how? How do I talk about work that I did in the past? I am proud that I made these things at the time that I made them. And for some of the projects I have a different view of who I was at the time and what I was doing. Most of the posts remain as they were, but for some I have added my current perspective on them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000//about.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Contact</title>
            <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;email&lt;/strong&gt;: allison@allisonburtch.net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;twitter&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;twitter.com/irl&quot;&gt;irl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;instagram&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;instagram.com/allisonburtch&quot;&gt;allisonburtch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;: coming soon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000//contact.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Press</title>
            <description>### PRESS
* [VICE](https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/vbw9db/could-we-blow-up-the-internet), Tim Maughan, &quot;Could we blow up the internet?&quot; 2019.
* [Rolling Stone](https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/in-battle-for-new-york-occupy-wall-streeters-turn-out-for-bernie-178430/), Tessa Stuart, &quot;In Battle for New York, Occupy Wall Streeters Turn Out for Bernie,&quot; 2016.
* [PBS](http://www.pbs.org/newshour/updates/drone-use-humanitarian-aid/), “Humanitarian efforts benefit from drones as ethical debate continues”, 2016.
* [NYTimes](http://www.nytimes.com/reuters/2016/12/15/technology/15reuters-malawi-aid-drones.html), Reuters, “U.N., Malawi to Explore Use of Drones to Deliver Faster Aid in Crises”, 2016.
* [Hyperallergic](http://hyperallergic.com/173513/cyberfeminists-go-deep-on-big-data-privacy-and-surveillance/),  Ben Valentine, “Cyberfeminists Go Deep on Big Data, Privacy, and Surveillance,” 2015. 
* [WIRED](http://www.wired.com/2014/10/fake-log-jams-your-phone/), Andy Greenberg, “This Fake Log Jams Your Phone So You’ll Shut Up and Enjoy Nature,” 2014. 
* [VICE](http://motherboard.vice.com/de/read/dieser-holzklotz-jammt-dein-telefon-damit-du-es-endlich-aus-der-hand-legst), Theresa Locker, &quot;Mit diesem Holzklotz blockst du Handy-Telefonie in deiner unmittelbaren Nähe,&quot; 2014. 
* [The Verge](http://www.theverge.com/2013/10/8/4815760/prism-breakup-is-hard-to-do-will-digital-privacy-ever-be-easy), Adi Robertson, “Breaking up with PRISM is hard to do: will digital privacy ever be easy?&quot; 2013.
* [The Village Voice](http://blogs.villagevoice.com/runninscared/2013/05/how_to_make_you.php), Nick Pinto, &quot;How to Make Your Dumb Phone Smart,&quot; 2013.
* [FastCo Design](http://www.fastcodesign.com/1672264/watch-how-to-keep-csi-off-your-dna-trail), Mark Wilson, “Watch: How To Keep CSI Off Your DNA Trail,” 2013. 
* [BBC News](http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-22487287), Video Interview, “Tisch school: Creative brains map a smarter future,” 2013.

### TALKS
* Digital Interaction and Surveillance, UT Austin, 2019
* Race, Gender and Surveillace, UT Austin, 2019
* NYU/MCC class on privacy, New York, NY2019
* Race, Gender and Surveillance class, Yale University, 2019
* &quot;Algorithmic Neoliberalism and Dialectical Data,&quot; Modern Language Association, Critical Algorithms, 2018, New York, NY
* Utopian Futures Workshop,  Youngstown State University, 2017, Youngstown, Ohio
* Race, Gender and Surveillance, University of Texas Austin, 2017, Texas
* UNICEF presentation, The Hague, 2017
* UNICEF Innovation presentation,Olin College of Engineering, November 2016, Boston, MA 
* “Art and Politics: Doing Both is Doing Neither”, Eyebeam Art &amp; Technology Center, October 2016, Brooklyn, NY
* Co-led TAILS workshop, Whitney Museum/Laura Poitras’ AstroNoise, April 2016, New York, NY 
* Columbia J School’s Brown Institute for Media Innovation, Feb 2016, New York, NY
* Drone “Do” Tank, UNICEF Innovation presentation, June 2016, Cape May, NJ
* Digital Ethics Symposium, “Data, Democracy and the Human Story: A Conversation with Members of Deep Lab”, Loyola University, November 2015, Chicago, IL
* Simone Browne's Race, Gender and Surveillance class, University of Texas Austin, October 2015, Austin, TX
* “Art, Design and the Future of Privacy,&quot; DIS Magazine/Pioneer Works, September 2015, Brooklyn, NY
* Listening Machines Conference, June 2015, New York, NY
* “[Anti-Utopias: What is to be done when everything is impossible](https://youtu.be/UeXz2NPCRco),” Panel moderator for Deep Lab Residency at NEW INC, May 2015, New York, NY
* Keynote talk for CASRO, May 2015, Philadelphia, PA
* ArtSec, Software Defined Radio, NEW INC, February 2015, New York, NY
* &quot;Snowed-In: Art in the Age of Surveillance,&quot; Fashion Institute of Technology, Manhattan, 2015 
* Biocode, &quot;DNA Spoofing,&quot; bioart, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, 2015
* Deep Lab presentation and talk, Carnegie Mellon University , December 2014, Pittsburgh, PA
* artist talk, NYU Polytechnic University, November 2014, Brooklyn, NY
* Eyebeam Art &amp; Technology Center, November 2014, Brooklyn, NY
* Brooklyn Public Library Cryptoparty, October 2014, Brooklyn, NY
* &quot;[Liberation Technology in a Gleaner’s Economy](https://youtu.be/-M8cNSyzo1g)&quot;, Open Source Hardware Summit, September 2014, Rome, Italy
* Institute for Technology and Society, July 2014, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
* NYU ITP, [Master’s thesis presentation](https://vimeo.com/allisonburtch/thesis), May 2014, New York, NY
* Digital Dumbo, December 2013, Brooklyn, NY

### SELECTED EXHIBITIONS:
* DNA Spoofing
	* Holocaust Memorial Museum of Budapest
	* National Museum of the History of Medicine of the Ukraine in Kiev
	* National Technical Museum Prague
	* Museum of Contemporary Art Northhampton
	* Baneful Medicine/The Cooper Union
	* Biocode/University of Pennsylvania
	* The Data Body as Artifact, Fukuoka City museum, Japan 
	* Panopticon, Utah Museum of Contemporary Art
	* Matter of Life MU Art Space, the Netherlands
	* Dataism - Museum Boijmans, Rotterdam
	* Utah Museum of Contemporary Art, “DNA Spoofing,” 2014
	* New York State Public Broadcasting Station, WMHT, “DNA Spoofing,” 2014
	* Art Hack Day, 319 Scholes, Brooklyn, NY 
* The New Aesthetic?, Brisbane, Australia, Queensland University of Technology, “Microphone Jammer,” 2015
* F.A.T. GOLD, San Francisco, CA, “Microphone Jammer,” 2015
* Eyebeam Annual Showcase, A Year of Alternative Maneuvers, Brooklyn, NY, “Microphone Jammer,” 2015
* Art Hack Day, Second Life Gallery, Providence, RI, “Your Very Own,” 2014
* Interactive Telecommunications Program Semester show at New York University, 2012, 2013, 2014 
* College Art Association, RTSpace, New York, NY, “Watching You,” 2012
* MOMA permanent collection, New York, NY, Occupied Wall Street Journal, 2012

### FELLOWSHIPS &amp; RESIDENCIES 
 * [Shuttleworth Foundation](https://shuttleworthfoundation.org/) flash grant, NOV 2014 
 * [Institute of Technology and Society](http://www.itsrio.org/), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, Global Fellows Program, Summer 2014, Policy study of the “Marco Civil da Internet,” the Brazilian government and telecommunications infrastructure in Rio, Sao Paolo and Brasilia.
 * [Parc Rousseau](http://parc-rousseau.fr/), Ermenonville, France, July-Aug 2015 - Researched and wrote about the new implications for public space given the multiplicity of wireless frequencies.
 * Deep Lab - [STUDIO for Creative Inquiry](http://studioforcreativeinquiry.org/projects/deep-lab), Pittsburgh, PA, December 2014
 * [Deep Lab](http://deeplab.net/) – NEW INC, New York, NY, May 2015
 * [Eyebeam Art and Technology Center](http://eyebeam.org/), Brooklyn, NY, Fall - Spring 2014 – 2015 
 * [Spruceton Inn Resident Artist](http://www.sprucetoninn.com/at-the-inn/artist-residency/), West Kill, NY, April 2015


</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000//press.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
